bestjobs.ph 2019-06-02

# Privacy policy

  1. **CONTROLLER**

**¿Who is responsible for processing your personal data?**

  * Identity: DGNET LTD. (“ **DGNET** ”)
  * Address: 10 York Place, Edinburgh, Midlothian, EH1 3EP, Scotland, United Kingdom.
  * E-mail: [contact form.](https://candidate.bestjobs.ph/contact/)

  2. **INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

As an individual user searching for employment openings (“Jobseeker”) we collect information about you in order for us to best provide our services. To create an account, you must provide personal data such as your first and last name, email address and a password.

Furthermore, you may include on your profile your academic information, work experience, personal skills, photograph (s), your city or location. Moreover, you may upload you resume on our website in Word or PDF format.

We also collect and store certain information associated with your use of our Site and mobile application (“App”), such as the job postings that you apply, the time and duration of your activity on our Site and the information you submit to our Site when you evaluate a company, which is not information publicly included on your profile nor available to the employers or recruiters.

On the other hand, we collect data from the cookies we use on our Site. You can review our Cookie Policy below.

We collect information automatically from your device, including your location, IP address, proxy server, operating system version, internet browser and plug-ins.

As a professional user, that is, employers or recruiting companies seeking to make available information regarding employment openings (collectively referred to as “Employers”) in order to create an account on our Site and use our services, you must provide us, besides the company information and identification, the contact information of the natural person who is accessing or using our Site as an employee or other representative of the Employer, and you represent and warrant that you have the authority to bind such Employer, as applicable, to this agreement. In particular, you must provide us your first name and last name, email address and a password.

  3. **PURPOSES OF THE PROCESSING**

**¿For what purposes do we process your personal data?**

DGNET purpose through the services offered on Bestjobs Site in the Philippines is to facilitate the contact between Jobseekers from the Philippines and Employers that offer employment openings in said country by offering them tools and services in order to support the job search process in the Philippines. 

As Jobseeker, when you register or access our Site and/or App, we use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * 3.1. In order for us to best provide you the services subscribed by you:  

    * Create an account on the Bestjobs Site.
    * To help you establish contact with the Employers through your application to their job postings. To this end, depending on the privacy settings you choose, the Employers may access to your contact information and your resume.
    * Be searched (according to the level of privacy you have chosen) through the database of Jobseekers registered in Bestjobs Site.
    * Edit and manage your resume on your private area. 
    * Automatically and free job alerts via electronic means.
    * Instant messaging service with Employers to facilitate the communication with them; when using the contact form or chat in the user area, you will be using our messaging service. Messages and advertisements are reviewed to prevent fraud, abuse or misuse of our services. 
    * Management of our services and daily business tasks, including reminders, technical alerts, updates, security alerts, and support messages, among others. When you use our customer service contact form, your data will be used to answer any queries you may have through this form.
    * To send commercial and promotional communications to inform you about our products, services and events.
    * To moderate and display the employer reviews, interview reviews, salary reports and other content you have submitted for the benefit of our other users.
  * 3.2. To improve the services that you subscribe by analyzing your use of the Site and/or App through Cookies in order to personalize the Site to your interests. You can manage the Cookies following the instructions stated in our Cookie Policy (see clause 8).  

  * 3.3. To create a commercial profile based on the information you provide to show you personalized advertising profiled through cookies, provided that we have your consent to do so. No automated decisions will be made based on this profile that produce legal or significant effects for you. The commercial profile that is created through cookies may be used by third party sites to show you personalized advertising.  

  * 3.4. To send you newsletters and promotions with advertising from others DGNET’s sites and partners. 
  * 3.5. To create aggregate and statistical information that does not identify you individually and provide us a better knowledge of the users or our Site/App as a whole and helps us to offer them a better service.
  * 3.6. To prevent abuse or potentially fraudulent or illegal activities in the use of our services (for example, avoiding service attacks, spamming, anomalous activity, among others).
  * 3.7. To provide data to a public authority or body, if the case, provided that such personal data is required in accordance to rules, laws and relevant regulations.

On the other hand, in case you are an Employer, when you register or access our Site we use your personal data for the following purposes:

  1. To provide our services, as well as resolve any queries you may have.  

  2. To send you newsletters and promotions with advertising from others DGNET’s sites and partners.
  3. To prevent abuse or fraudulent activity in the use of our services (for example, avoiding service attacks, spamming, anomalous activity, among others).
  4. To analyse your use of our Site in order to develop and improve its functioning and our services. 
  5. To provide data to a public authority or body, if the case, provided that such personal data is required in accordance to rules, laws and relevant regulations. 

  4. **PERIOD FOR WHICH THE PERSONAL DATA WILL BE STORED**

**¿How long will we store your data?**

The data provided by you will be stored while the contractual and commercial relationship with us lasts, until you request its erasure, and also during the necessary time to comply with relevant legal obligations. 

  5. **LEGAL BASIS**

**¿Which is the legal basis for the processing of your data?**

The legal basis for the collection and processing of your data is the performance of a contract with DGNET regarding the purposes stated in point 3.1, in order to properly manage and improve the services provided to you.

The legal basis regarding the purposes set out in point 3.2, 3.3. and 3.4. relies on your consent.

Also, the collection and processing of your data for the purposes set out in point 3.5. and 3.6 is the legitimate interest pursued by DGNET as data controller.

Additionally, for the purposes set out in point 3.7, the legal basis relies upon the compliance with the relevant legal obligations of DGNET.

On the other hand, in the case of the Employers, the legal basis for the collection and processing of data regarding the purposes stated in letter (a) is the performance of a contract with DGNET in order to properly manage and improve the services provided to you. As for the purpose established in letter (b) the legal basis relies on your consent. Also, regarding the purposes set out in letter (c) and (d), the legal basis is the legitimate interest pursued by DGNET as data controller. Finally, for the purpose set out in letter e), the legal basis relies upon the compliance with the relevant legal obligations of DGNET.

  6. **RECIPIENTS OF THE PERSONAL DATA**

**¿To which recipients your data is legitimately disclosed?**

As Jobseeker, if you apply for a particular job through our Site, we will disclose your personal information to the Employer to facilitate the contact with the latter. 

Whether you are a Jobseeker or an Employer, your data may be processed by suppliers -including companies pertaining to DGNET’ corporate group- which provide us services, such as hosting, alerts, maintenance, support, marketing, web development, CRM, among others. DGNET has subscribed the relevant data processing agreements with each supplier that provides services to DGNET in order to ensure that your personal data are treated with due confidentiality, adequate protection and only for the purpose for which they have been communicated, having limited access to your information. Also, your data may be transfer for compliance with a legal obligation. 

  7. **RIGHTS OF THE USERS**

**¿What are your rights and how can you exercise them?**

Regarding your personal data you have the following data protection rights:

  * Access your data: you can request us a copy of your personal information.

  * Update and rectify your data: you can edit your personal data through your private area of your account. Moreover, you can request us the amendment, update and correction of your data if they are not accurate. 

  * Object to the processing and to delate your data: you have the right to ask us to restrict processing of your personal information and to delete your personal data, except for compelling legitimate reasons or the exercise or defense of possible claims.

  * Request portability of your personal information: when technically possible, you may request the transfer of your data to another controller, without affecting the lawfulness of the processing based on your prior consent to its withdrawal.

You can exercise your rights by contacting us using the contact details provided below; we will handle your request in accordance with applicable law.

Regarding the data provided to the Employers to whom you have contacted, you can exercise your rights before them.

The abovementioned rights are subject to certain limitations, as provided by applicable laws. Individual requests will be completed within the time allotted by relevant regulations, which starts to run from the point of DGNET confirming your request. Where permitted, please note there may be a charge for subsequent requests from the same individual, which will be determined by DGNET and only imposed to the extent permitted by applicable law.

  8. **COOKIE POLICY**

**¿What are Cookies?**

Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored on your computer, mobile phone, or other device when you first visit a page and that activates the functionalities of Bestjobs Site. For instance, cookies allow us to identify your device, give you secure access to Bestjobs, and even help us know if someone tries to access your account from another device. Cookies also track the user session, improve the loading time of a website, avoid displaying repetitive information and help us to show ads relevant to you.

**¿Why we use Cookies?**

We use Cookies for a variety of purposes, such as to improve your online experience, to offer you personalized content through our Site and App. Also, to offer you relevant revenue-generating advertising based on your interests that allows us to maintain free access to other services.

**¿What types of Cookies do we use?**

We use Cookies on the Site and App for the following purposes:

  1. **Autentication:** They allow you to display the right information and personalize your experience and help us determine whether or not you have signed into our Site or App.  

  2. **Preference and Features:** Are essential to the Site functioning, they help to enable features, help us provide you with personalized content such as showing you your recent search activity. For instance, they help avoid showing certain information pages that you are not interested in.

**¿What third-party Cookies do we use?**

  1. **Analytics:** They allow to monitor our Site and App performance. For instance, how our users and visitors use the Site or App. For instance, analyze behavior patterns, number of users accessing, sections visited, duration of browsing, create statistical reports on web traffic, global audience and audience of a given advertising campaign. 

The third-parties that may have access to this information are:

    * Google Analytics: 

<http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/technologies/cookies>

    * Score Card Research: 

<http://www.scorecardresearch.com/privacy.aspx>

In order to consult the privacy policy regarding the cookies of the referred third parties, we recommend accessing their legal conditions through the previous links.

  2. **Advertising:** They allow to efficiently manage the ads offered on the Site, the adaptation of the content to the service requested, or the use made of the web portal. In that way we can provide the users relevant and personalized advertising. In addition, cookies are necessary to manage advertising campaigns, by tracking various patterns such as the number of times an ad has been viewed, or to improve and manage the exposure of ads, avoiding the user the advertising that has already been shown. 

Advertising cookies also enable us to inform, optimise and report on our advertising impressions, other uses of advertising services, interactions with these impressions and advertising services have an impact on visits to the site, and to offer advertising based on previous visits to our website.

The third-parties we work with and that use this type of Cookies are: 

    * DoubleClick: 

<https://www.google.com/doubleclick>

    * Appnexus: 

<https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/cookie-policy>

    * Criteo: 

<https://www.criteo.com/cookie-policy/>

    * Clickio: 

<https://adexchange.clickio.com/site/>

    * OpenX: 

<https://www.openx.com/legal/privacy-policy/>

In order to consult the privacy policy regarding the cookies of the referred third parties, we recommend accessing their legal conditions through the previous links.

**Disabling Cookies**

You can disable and/or delete Cookies by following the instructions on your Internet browser. However, please note that doing so will significantly reduce your ability to browse our website and may even make it incompatible with your interests or needs. Users can choose at any time which cookies they wish to activate through their browser settings:

  * Chrome from: [https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=es](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=es)
  * Explorer from: <https://support.microsoft.com/es-es/help/278835/how-to-delete-cookie-files-in-internet-explorer>
  * Firefox from: <https://support.mozilla.org/es/kb/habilitar-y-deshabilitar-cookies-sitios-web-rastrear-preferencias>
  * Safari from: <https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=es_ES>

**Opting Out of Cookies**

  * Opt-out for each type of cookie: the use of this system may install an "opt-out" cookie on your computer to deactivate the cookie in particular.
  * Third-parties tools available: you can find online tools that can detect all cookies on each website visited and disable them.
  * Opt-out systems available for Google Analytics: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

  9. **SECURITY SAFEGUARDS**

DGNET works to ensure the security and confidentiality of your personal information. To that end, we have employ security and technical measures to help protect against its loss, misuse and alteration. However, while we strive to protect your information, we cannot guarantee 100 % its security. Moreover, you are responsible for keeping your password secret and in control of your personal information. We ask you to be careful with who you share your information with. 

  10. **MINIMUM AGE**

To access or use our Site or App you must be at least 16 years of age or more. If you are under 18 years of age or under the age of majority in your jurisdiction, your use of our Site must be under parental, guardian or another responsible adult supervision. If we become aware that a minor has provided us with personal information without parental consent, we will remove such information and terminate the minor account.

  11. **CONTACT INFORMATION**

If you wish to exercise any of your rights or if you have any queries or complaints regarding this Privacy and Cookie Policy, you can contact us:

  * By email: [contact form.](https://candidate.bestjobs.ph/contact/)
  * By mail to the following address: 10 York Place, Edinburgh, Midlothian, EH1 3EP, Scotland, United Kingdom. 

You must provide as much information as possible about your enquiry: name and surname, e-mail address you use for our website and the reasons for your request.
